高清电影网 http://M1080.com 提供字幕下载
本片根据真实故事改编
新来的黑鬼们 都给我听好了
All right now. Y'all fresh niggers.
朝根茎砍下去
Get in them cane.
卖力点
Make it sing.
连根茎拔出来
Take the cane out.
把上面砍掉
Cut my tops.
剥皮
Clean the shucks off.
然后扔到那一堆给种植组
Throw it on a pile for the planting gang.
对了 根茎又不会蹦起来咬你一口
Now, them cane ain't gonna jump up and bite you.
所以别怕
Don't shy back.
上吧 小伙子们! 上呀!
Rush here, boys! Rush here!
# 我主 #
# My Lord #
# 骄阳 #
# Sunshine #
# 我主 #
# My Lord #
# 主啊 #
# Lord, Lord #
# 我母 #
# My ma #
# 已故 #
# She dead #
# 我父 #
# My pa #
# 亦亡 #
# He dead #
# 我主 #
# My Lord #
# 骄阳 #
# Sunshine #
# 我主 #
# My Lord #
# 骄阳 #
# Sunshine #
# 天色已暗 #
# Is late #
# 如日中天 #
# In high #
# 我主 #
# My Lord #
# 骄阳 #
# Sunshine #
# 我主 #
# My Lord #
# 主啊 #
# Lord, Lord #
# 我母 #
# My ma #
# 已故 #
# She dead #
# 我父 #
# My pa #
# 亦亡 #
# He dead #
# 我主 #
# My Lord #
# 骄阳 #
# Sunshine #
# 我主 #
# My Lord #
# 是的 主人 #
# Yes, sir #
为奴十二年
好了好了
All right, all right, all right, all right.
躺床上去
Into bed.
躺床上去 多谢你们的奏乐
Into bed. Thank you for the music.
- 睡吧  - 噢
- Come on.  - Ouch.
钻进去 睡吧
Get in there. Come on.
亲我一下
Give me a kiss.
我爱你 玛格丽特
I love you, Margaret.
我也爱您
I love you, too.
晚安
Sleep well.
这个归我保管
I'll take this.
好好睡觉 别再吵闹
I don't want to hear any more noise.
你要走整整三周零两天
Three weeks and two days.
这是习俗
It is the custom.
我很好奇我不在的时候你怎么办
I wonder what you will do without me.
我也不会闲着
I won't stay idle.
亲爱的 这很赚钱
Darling, it's good money.
要是我能独享你的厨技该多好
If only I didn't have to share your cooking with other people.
本来就是嘛
You don't.
听妈妈的话 阿朗佐 要乖噢
Be good for your mother. Okay, Alonzo?
能亲我一下吗? 真棒
Can I get a kiss, please? Thank you.
一路顺风
Travel safely.
注意安全
Stay safely.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
说曹操 曹操就到
Devil call his name, there he is now.
诺瑟普先生!
Mr. Northup!
这两位先生您或许愿意认识一下
I have two gentlemen whose acquaintance you should make.
布朗先生和汉密尔顿先生
Misters Brown and Hamilton.
您好
Sir.
诺瑟普先生 这两位先生...
Mr. Northup, these two gentlemen...
在打听杰出人士...
were inquiring about distinguished individuals...
我刚才正说到...
and I was just this very moment...
所罗门・诺瑟普是一位专家级的小提琴演奏者
saying Solomon Northup is an expert player on the violin.
正说到您呢
He was indeed.
摩恩先生心地真好
Mr. Moon is being overly gracious.
既然他心地这么好
Well, taking into consideration
您又如此谦逊...
his graciousness and your modesty...
我们能耽误您一会儿跟您聊聊吗 先生?
may we trouble you for a moment of your time to converse, sir?
没问题
Of course.
祝好
Good day.
马戏团?
A circus?
那是我们的常规人员
That is our usual employee.
大家目前在华盛顿城内
The company currently in the city of Washington.
用马戏团这个字眼来描述...
Circus is too constricting a word...
与我们同行的那些奇人异士未免有些不全面
to describe the talented and merry band with which we travel.
应该说是一个举世未见的奇观
It is a spectacle unlike most have ever witnessed.
来自非洲大地最黑暗角落的生灵
Creatures from the darkest Africa
尚未有文明人亲眼见证
as yet unseen by civilized man.
来自遥远东方的杂技演员...
Acrobats from the Orient...
能将身躯扭曲到最不可思议的地步
who contort themselves in the most confounding manners.
还有在变戏法界...
And I myself in aide of Mr. Brown...
全球享有胜名的表演家布朗先生
an internationally renowned practitioner
以及身为他助理的我
in the art of prestidigitation.
我们这一小段时间离开大家伙儿
We are on our way thither to rejoin
藉由自己的展出赚了一小笔...
the company having left for a short time...
现在正回去和大家重聚
to make a small profit from our own exhibitions.
我们向摩恩先生打听是因为...
The reason for our inquiry with Mr. Moon...
对了 我们为演出寻觅优质的音乐
Yes. We had just a devil of a time
着实费了一番脑筋
in procuring music for our entertainments.
真正有天赋的人看来太稀缺啦
Men of true talents are seemingly in short supply.
谢谢夸奖 先生
Thank you, sir.
要是我们能说服您与我们一同去华盛顿...
If we could persuade you to accompany us as far as Washington...
我们可以付您一天一美元...
We could give you one dollar for each day's services...
而在我们的演出中表演每晚是三美元
and three dollars for every night played at our performances.
另外 我们会为您提供足够的路费...
In addition, we would provide sufficient pay...
让您两周后回到萨拉托加
for your return here to Saratoga, two weeks from today.
欢迎来到华盛顿 所罗门
Welcome to Washington, Solomon.
汉密尔顿 你懂得真多
Hamilton, you know too much.
还有人说不够呢
Some say not enough.
所罗门 43美元 都是你的了
Solomon, 43 dollars. All to you.
这可比我的工资多得多了
That is far more than my wages amount to.
这周赚得盆满钵满 先生
It's been a most profitable week, sir.
- 干杯  - 干杯
- Cheers.  - Cheers.
干杯
Cheers.
再来一杯
Another.
先生们 你们真是太慷慨了
Gentlemen, your generosity is extraordinary.
而您的才华也是无可否认的
And your talents are undeniable.
嗯 敬所罗门
Mmm. To Solomon.
干杯
Cheers.
啊!
Ugh!
没事的 所罗门
It's all right, Solomon.
没什么好丢脸的
There's no shame in it.
根本没必要
No shame at all.
汉密尔顿 咱们得加快速度了
Hamilton, we must hurry.
把人灌个烂醉
One too many libation.
我们就成功一半了
We're halfway there.
真抱歉...
So sorry...
我们听不到的
We won't hear it. We won't.
让他睡吧 汉密尔顿
Let him sleep, Hamilton.
嗯 好好休息一晚上
Mmm. A good night's rest.
到了明天...
And tomorrow...
明天你就焕然一新
tomorrow you will feel as well and refreshed
如同外面的世界天翻地覆一般
as if the earth were new again.
汉密尔顿 我们什么也帮不到他了
Hamilton, there's nothing more we can do for him.
这便是可悲之处
Such is the pity.
小子 现在什么感觉?
Well, boy, how do you feel now?
我... 我叫所罗门・诺瑟普
My name... My name is Solomon Northup.
我是一个自由人 是纽约萨拉托加的居民
I'm a free man. A resident of Saratoga, New York.
我妻子和孩子也住那里 他们也是自由人
The residence of my wife and children who are equally free.
无论如何 你们无权扣留我
And you have no right whatsoever to detain me.
你不是个自由人
You're not any free man.
我告诉你...
And I promise you...
一旦恢复自由身
I promise you upon my liberation
我一定要得到公正
I will have satisfaction for this wrong.
你倒是试试啊
Resolve this.
拿出文件来
Produce your papers.
你才不是什么自由人
You're no free man.
你也不是萨拉托加的
And you ain't from Saratoga.
你是佐治亚的
You're from Georgia.
你不是个自由人
You ain't a free man.
你不过是个从佐治亚逃跑的
You're nothing but a Georgia runaway.
你不过是个从佐治亚逃跑的...
You're just a runaway nigger...
黑鬼
from Georgia.
你是个奴隶!
You're a slave!
你是个佐治亚的奴隶!
You're a Georgia slave!
你是奴隶吗?
Are you a slave?
不是
No.
救命
Help.
救我
Help me.
救救我!
Help me!
来人啊!
Somebody help me!
救命!
Help!
你身上那件已经是破烂了
That old thing of yours is just rags and tatters.
你得穿得像样点
You need something proper to wear.
穿上吧
Go on, put it on.
这就对了
There.
看起来好多了
That's fine.
好多了
都不怀感激之情?
Got no gratitude?
别拿走 那是我妻子送我的
No. That's from my wife.
不过是一堆破烂
Rags and tatters.
一堆破烂而已
去啊 洗干净
Go on, wash up.
还有这个男孩子 把他也洗干净
The boy, too. Get him clean.
快搓
Scrub now.
你知道我妈妈什么时候会来吗?
Do you know when my mama will come?
让他闭嘴!
Hush him up!
妈妈! 妈妈!
Mama! Mama!
安静点
Quiet.
- 安静点  - 妈妈!
- Quiet, please.  - Mama!
让他闭嘴!
Hush him up!
你妈妈会来的 我发誓她一定会来的 但你现在一定不能出声
Your mother will come, I swear she will. But you must be silent.
别出声
Be silent.
我们需要一个有同情心的倾听者
We need a sympathetic ear.
一个讲清楚我们处境的机会
An opportunity to explain our situation.
那你倒是说说 谁会是那个有同情心的倾听者呢?
Who, in your estimation, is that sympathetic ear?
与我同行的那两个
The two men I journeyed with.
我敢肯定他们此时此刻正展开调查
I'm certain they're making enquiries at this very moment.
我倒是很肯定他们这时候
I'd be just as certain they're counting
正数着把你卖到这儿来赚的钞票呢
the money paid for delivering you to this place.
他们不是绑匪 他们是艺术家 一同表演的人
They were not kidnappers, they were artists. Fellow performers.
你确定吗?
You know that?
你确定这是他们的真实身份吗?
You know for certain who they were?
现实的结果是我们被向南转移了
The reality to come is us being transported southward.
我敢猜是新奥尔良
New Orleans, if I was to venture.
我们抵达之后 便会被带到市场
After we arrive, we'll be put to market.
然后嘛...
And beyond that...
我想既然沦为奴隶 也就没什么别的结果了吧
Well, I suppose once in a slave state, there's only one outcome.
不
No.
约翰 我这么说不是为了让你发无名火的
I don't say that to give you empty agitation, John.
对于你们来说是这样
For y'all, there ain't nothing but that.
但我可不是被绑架的
But John wasn't kidnapped.
我是被用来抵债的 仅此而已
John's just being held as debt, that's all.
主人还清他的债务我就得救了
Master pay his debt and John be redeemed.
小子 我们的主人不会来救我们的
Boy, our masters will not come for us.
我为大家感到抱歉 但事实如此
John is sorry for y'all, but that's how it be.
不管你们去哪儿 都没我的事
Where you're going, you're going without John.
- 妈妈  - 兰德尔!
- Mama!  - Randall!
妈妈!
Mama!
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
谢天谢地
Thank you, God.
来 起床了
Come on. Get up.
- 我说了 起来了!  - 不 别...
- I said, get up!  - No, don't...
我不想听你废话! 到院子里去
I don't want to hear you talk! Get in the yard.
别对我孩子这样!
Not my children!
一惊一乍什么 只是次短途旅行而已
Ain't no need for all that. Just taking a little trip, that's all.
坐在船上的时候
Don't want to frighten the children
可不想吓着孩子吧?
over a little boat ride, do you?
我的主人会还清债务的
John's master gonna pay his debt.
排好队!
Line up!
我的主人会还清债务的!
His master gonna pay his debt!
你们连个屁都不许放!
I don't want to hear a word out of none of you!
一个也不行
Not a one.
好了 走吧
All right, come on.
走吧
Move. Come on.
孩子 来 走吧
Come on, child. Come on.
跟着你妈妈
Follow your mama.
来吧 孩子
Come on, boy.
上台阶
Up these stairs.
从马车上下来
Get down out of that wagon. Come on.
走吧 动作快!
Come on. Move it!
走吧!
Let's go!
往上 上台阶
Up, up, up the stairs.
走吧
Come on, let's go.
动作快点!
Come on, move it!
好了 接着走
All right, come on.
嘿 你 起来
Hey, you. Get up.
在这儿坐下
Sit down, right there.
来
Come on.
这儿 坐下就好
Right there. Just sit down.
都高兴点 别郁郁寡欢的
Cheer up and don't be so cast down.
要是想活下去 尽可能少当出头鸟
If you want to survive, do and say as little as possible.
不要告诉任何人你的真实身份 也不要告诉任何人你会读会写
Tell no one who you really are and tell no one you can read and write.
除非你想成为棺材里的黑鬼
Unless you want to be a dead nigger.
现在可以闭嘴了吧
Now keep your mouth shut.
我说咱们该跟他们斗
I say we fight.
船员并不多
The crew is fairly small.
要是他们考虑周到的话 他们很可能火力充足
Were it well planned, I believe they could be strong-armed.
区区三个人不可能跟整个船上的对着干
Three can't go against the whole crew.
这儿其他人都是黑奴
The rest here are niggers.
地地道道的黑奴
Born and bred slaves.
黑奴是不会反抗的
Niggers ain't got no stomach for a fight.
一个都不会
Not a damn one.
我只知道 要是被运到那里...
All's I know, if we get where we're traveling...
我们不如死了算了
we'll wish we'd died trying.
不要意气用事
Survival's not about certain death,
只有低调行事才能活下去
it's about keeping your head down.
几天之前 我还在家里...
Days ago, I was with my family...
和家人在一起
in my home.
但现在一切都没了
Now you tell me all is lost.
"别告诉任何人自己的真实身份" 这样就能活命了?
"Tell no one who I am." That's the way to survive?
我要的不只是活命
Well, I don't want to survive.
而是生活
I want to live.
真羡慕
Better off.
太羡慕他了
Better than us.
怎么没看到他
I don't see him.
克莱门斯!
Clemens!
- 克莱门斯・瑞!  - 主人!
- Clemens Ray!  - Master!
- 克莱门斯!  - 瑞老爷!
- Clemens!  - Master Ray, sir!
瑞老爷!
Master Ray!
谁是管事的?
Who's in charge here?
我是船长!
I'm the captain!
我是乔纳斯・瑞先生
I'm Mr. Jonus Ray.
我的律师这有份证明...
My solicitor has documentation...
黑奴克莱门斯・瑞是我的财产
verifying the negro known as Clemens Ray is my property.
我可没听说过这件事
I know nothing of this arrangement.
立刻将他归还
You are ordered to return that property
否则你将面临盗窃罪起诉
immediately or be charged with thievery.
放了他!
Free him!
主人
Master.
瑞老爷
Master Ray, sir.
克莱门斯!
Clemens!
- 克莱门斯!  - 把他带回去!
- Clemens!  - Get him back!
克莱门斯!
Clemens!
帕克先生
Mr. Parker.
诺瑟普先生 诺瑟普夫人
Ah, Mr. Northup. Mrs. Northup.
所罗门 请允许我给您介绍一款新式领巾
Solomon, could I interest you in a new cravat?
从法国来的百分百丝绸
Pure silk, by way of the French.
我们想买一个新旅行袋 我夫人出门用
We're in need of a fresh carryall for my Mrs.'s travels.
不买别的
Nothing more.
年关将近
The year has passed already.
您又要去桑迪山出差了?
Off to work at Sandy Hill again?
没错
I am.
有一款正合适
I have just the thing.
和您的风格非常相配...
Something to suit your style...
而且很结实 40英里来回绝对没问题
and yet sturdy enough for the 40-mile round trip.
挺不错的
It's beautiful.
多少钱?
At what price?
我们买了
We will take it.
孩子们 快过来看看爸爸给我买了什么
Children, come see what you father has just purchased for me.
先生 稍等一下 这就过去
One moment, sir, and you'll be assisted.
- 帕克先生  - 什么事?
- Mr. Parker.  - Sir?
价钱能不能再商量一下
If we could discuss the price.
不好意思 所罗门 不好意思 诺瑟普夫人
Oh, forgive me, Solomon. Forgive me, Mrs. Northup.
有客人来了 欢迎您 先生
A customer waits. Welcome, sir.
随便看吧 但是小心钱包
Shop well, sir, but mind your wallet.
请别在意那位先生说的
Pay no attention to this gentleman's nonsense.
贾斯珀!
Jasper!
很抱歉打扰了 先生
My regrets for the intrusion, sir.
没关系
No intrusion.
过得愉快 先生
Good day, sir.
您也愉快
Good day.
贾斯珀 出来
Jasper, out.
很好 很好
Very good. Very good.
点一下名 艾来萨!
Let's see, here. Eliza!
听到名字站起来 艾来萨
Stand up when you hear your name. Eliza.
莱西!
Lethe!
约翰
John.
奥伦
Oren.
普莱特
Platt.
站起来
Stand up.
你符合了条件
You fit the description given.
我叫你的名字 你为什么不站起来?
Why didn't you answer when called?
我不叫普莱特
My name is not Platt.
我叫...
My name...
你就叫普莱特
Your name is Platt.
船长 把这些黑奴带到我的车上
Captain, get these niggers to my cart.
嗯
Mmm.
快走
Move.
在后屋为您准备的这些
I believe I have something very much
我相信会令您很满意的
to your liking in the back room.
请跟我来
Follow me, please.
好了 你们可以随便看...
Yes. Now, inspect them at your leisure...
但我希望你们注意一下年轻的埃兹拉
but I ask you to pay particular regard to young Ezra here.
健壮的四肢
Incredibly sound limbs.
我都没见过体格这么好的
I have never seen anything quite like him.
还有这家伙 很不错吧? 嗯?
And this marvelous creature. Can you believe it? Mmm?
她会是个出色的女仆
She'll make a fine lady's maid.
您说是吧?
Madam?
请随意挑选吧
So, inspect at your leisure.
尽情地看 这边还有点心
Take your time. Help yourself to refreshments.
先生们 有感兴趣的吗? 嗯?
Gentlemen, what catches your fancy here? Hmm?
这个小伙子?
This boy? Yes?
张嘴 张大一点
Open your mouth. Open wider.
看吧 他从来都没生过病
Look in there. Never been sick a day in his life.
请允许我介绍一下玛莎
And I call particular attention to Martha.
她做糕点很拿手
She is an excellent pastry cook.
啊 福特先生
Ah, Mr. Ford.
见到您真荣幸 您有感兴趣的吗?
Splendid seeing you, sir. What catches your fancy?
这个小伙子? 他很结实
This lad? He's very brawny.
普莱特和艾来萨一共多少钱?
How much for the ones Platt and Eliza?
好吧
Ah, yes.
普莱特一千美元 哦
A thousand for Platt. Uh... Oh.
这个黑奴可是很有两下子的
This is a nigger of considerable talent, I assure you.
艾来萨七百美元
700 for Eliza.
价格公道
My fairest price.
嗯
Mmm.
用票据付款行吗?
You will accept a note?
求您了 先生 别把我们一家分开
Please, sir. Do not divide my family.
别把我从我的孩子们身边带走
Do not take me unless you take my children.
艾来萨! 闭嘴!
Eliza! Quiet!
我一定会对您忠心耿耿的
You will have the most faithful slave in me.
一定会对您忠心耿耿的
The most faithful slave that has ever lived.
求求您别拆散我们
But I beg that you do not separate us.
那个男孩多少钱?
Your price for the boy?
艾来萨! 别说了!
Eliza! Stop it!
谁管你哭不哭
I will give you something to cry about.
兰德尔 上前来 过来
Randall, come forward. Come, come, come.
您看到这个男孩多健康了吧?
Now, do you see how fit this boy is?
就像成熟的果实
Like ripe fruit.
能把手杖借我吗? 看这个
May I take your stick a moment? Observe this.
兰德尔 跳起来 跳起来
Randall, jump, jump, jump. Run, run, run.
很好! 再高点
Very good! Higher.
您看到了吧
Now, you see this.
他长大肯定是个壮汉
It's very likely he will grow into a fine beast.
六百美元
600 for the boy.
一口价
Fair and final.
好吧
Done.
太好了 请稍等一下
Superb. A moment, please.
福特先生
Mr. Ford.
- 求您了  - 艾来萨!
- Please.  - Eliza!
小女孩多少钱?
How much for the little girl?
啊...
Ah...
她对你来说没什么用
You have no use for her.
她太小了 卖不了多少钱
One so young will bring you no profit.
不 不 那个女孩我不卖
No, no, no. I cannot sell the girl.
她可是棵摇钱树
No, there's heaps and piles of money to be made from her.
她可是个美人 血统很纯正
She's a beauty. One of the regular bloods.
和那些厚唇 只会埋头摘棉花的黑奴不一样
None of your thick-lipped, bullet-heated, cotton-picking niggers, here.
那是她的孩子
Her child, man.
求您了
Please.
看在上帝的份上 你就不能有一丝怜悯吗?
For God's sake, are you not sentimental in the least?
我的怜悯之心和价格是成正比的
My sentimentality extends the length of a coin.
求您了
God, please.
您是要全买下来 还是全不买 福特先生?
Now do you take this lot, Mr. Ford, or do you pass on them?
求您了 求您了
Please, please. Please.
我要买普莱特和艾来萨
I will take the ones Platt and Eliza.
艾来萨和普莱特 成交
Sold, Eliza and Platt.
我不会离开我的孩子们的!
I will not go without my children!
别哭哭啼啼的!
Goddamn sniveling wench!
不要把他们带走!
You will not take them from me!
该死的! 把她拖走 凯普!
God damn you! Get her out of here, Cape!
求您了! 不要!
Please! No! No!
把她拖出去 该死的!
Get her out of here, god damn it!
普莱特 拿着小提琴 拉个曲子
Platt, get your fiddle. Play, play, play something.
你不要哭了 该死的妇人!
I will give you something to cry about, you goddamned witch!
把她拖走 凯普! 快点!
Get her out of here, Cape! Out, now!
妈妈! 妈妈!
Mama! Mama! Mama!
好了
Yes.
福特先生 合作愉快
Mr. Ford, a pleasure.
你把那些黑奴都买了吗?
Did you bring all those niggers?
你买了两个?
Two of them? You got two?
查平先生
Mr. Chapin.
有个在哭 她为什么哭?
This one's crying. Why is this one crying?
她和孩子们分开了
Separated from her children.
- 天啊  - 帮不了她
- Oh, dear.  - It couldn't be helped.
可怜的女人
Poor, poor woman.
- 查平先生  - 在 先生
- Mr. Chapin.  - Yes, sir.
明天你带他俩
Tomorrow, you have to take these two
去磨坊工作
up to the mill and start them working.
现在让他们休整一下
For now, make them adequate.
给他们吃点东西 好好休息
Fix them a meal and have them rest themselves.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
下来吧
Come on, now.
快下来! 别磨蹭!
Come on! Don't dawdle!
吃点东西 再好好休息
Something to eat, and some rest.
你很快就会忘掉孩子们的
Your children will soon be forgotten.
你们这些新来的黑奴可能不知道...
For all of you raw niggers that don't know...
我叫约翰・底比斯 是威廉姆・福特家的首席木匠
my name is John Tibeats, William Ford's chief carpenter.
你们应该叫我"主人"
You will refer to me as "Master."
查平先生是这个农场的监工
Mr. Chapin is the overseer on this plantation.
你们也得称他"主人"
You, too, will refer to him as "Master."
鼓掌吧
So, clap your hands.
就像这样 快点
Like this. Come on.
快点鼓掌
Come on, now. Clap your hands.
# 黑奴跑 黑奴跳 #
# Nigger run Nigger flew #
# 黑奴撕碎衣衫 #
# Nigger tore his shirt in two #
# 快跑快跑 奴隶主会抓到你 #
# Run, run The Pattyroller will get you #
# 黑奴快跑 快点跑 #
# Run, nigger, run Well, you better get away #
没错 就是这样
That's right. Like you mean it.
# 黑奴快快跑 #
# Nigger run Run so fast #
# 把头伸进了马蜂窝 #
# Stove his head in a hornet's nest #
# 快跑快跑 奴隶主会抓到你 #
# Run, run The Pattyroller will get you #
# 黑奴快跑 快点跑 #
# Run, nigger, run Well, you better get away #
# 黑奴快跑 奴隶主会抓到你 #
# nigger, run The Pattyroller will get you #
# 黑奴快跑 快点跑 #
# Run, nigger, run Well, you better get away #
# 有人说黑奴从不偷窃 #
# Some folk say a nigger don't steal #
# 我就抓到过三次 #
# I caught three in my corn field #
# 一个偷了一蒲式耳 一个偷了两加仑 #
# One has a bushel And one has a peck #
# 还有一个脖子上缠了一捆绳子 #
# One has a rope It was hung around his neck #
# 黑奴快跑 奴隶主会抓到你 #
# Run nigger, run The Pattyroller will get you #
# 黑奴快跑 快点跑 #
# Run, nigger, run Well, you better get away #
# 黑奴快跑 奴隶主会抓到你 #
# Run nigger, run The Pattyroller will get you #
# 黑奴快跑 快点跑 #
# Run, nigger, run Well, you better get away #
# 嘿 奴隶主先生 别抓我 #
# Hey, Mr. Pattyroller Don't catch me #
# 去抓那个躲在树后的黑奴吧 #
# Catch that nigger behind that tree #
# 黑奴快跑 奴隶主会抓到你 #
# Run nigger, run The Pattyroller will get you #
# 黑奴快跑 快点跑 #
# Run, nigger, run Well, you better get away #
# 黑奴快跑 奴隶主会抓到你 #
# Run nigger, run The Pattyroller will get you #
# 黑奴快跑 快点跑 #
# Run, nigger, run Well, you better get away #
# 黑奴快跑 奴隶主会抓到你 #
# Run nigger, run The Pattyroller will get you #
# 黑奴快跑 快点跑 #
# Run, nigger, run Well, you better get away #
"我乃亚伯拉罕之神 以撒之神...
"I am the God of Abraham, the God of Isaac...
雅各之神
and the God of Jacob.
当世人听到这些
And when the multitude heard this,
都被他的教义所震惊
they were astonished at his doctrine.
他们中有一位律师...
And then one of them, which was a lawyer...
问了他一个有趣的问题"
asked him a question, tempting him."
小溪很深 可以载船
The creek is plenty deep enough to sail.
船上装满货物也没问题
Even with a boat full of load.
从工地到到河口
The distance from the work area
那边的距离...
to the point on the latter bayou...
从水路走要比陆路近好几英里
is several miles by water fewer than land.
我觉得这样的运输费用
It occurs to me that the expense of transportation
会大幅度减少...
would be materially diminished...
"大幅度减少"?
"Materially diminished"?
如果我们走水路的话
If we use the waterway.
你是工程师 还是黑奴?
Are you an engineer, or a nigger?
让他把话说完
Let the man say his piece.
这是很多工程师精心设计的
It's a scheme. Plenty of engineers have schemed similarly.
那里河道太窄了
The passes are too tight.
我认为最窄的地方也有12英寸
I reckon them at more than 12 feet at their most narrow.
只要让一队黑奴去开路
Wide enough for a tub to traverse
就足够让船通行了
if a team of niggers cleared it out.
你懂运输和土地改革吗?
And you know what of transport and terraforming?
我在山普伦运河当过修理工...
I labored repairing the Champlain canal...
在威廉・范・诺特维克手下
on the section over which William Van Nortwick was superintendent.
我用所得雇了几个得力助手...
With my earnings, I hired several efficient hands to assist me...
还参与了
and entered into contracts for
从尚普兰湖...
the transportation of large rafts of timber...
运输木材的大宗合同...
from Lake Champlain to Troy.
不管你信不信 反正我是信了
Well, I'll admit to being impressed even if you won't.
召集人马 大显身手吧
Collect a team. See what good you can do.
好了吗? 搞定它!
You good? Clear it out!
二 三...
Two, three...
# 一切已迟 #
# Too late for me #
# 活着或死 #
# I live or die #
# 伏身哭泣 #
# Lay down and cry #
# 哦 我累了 #
# Hey, boy I'm tired #
# 亲爱的主啊 #
# My lord Sometimes #
# 让我变强吧 #
# I'm strong Yes, sir #
# 让我变壮吧 #
# I'm tall Yes, sir #
普莱特 你真是个天才
Platt, you are a marvel.
怎么这么久才过来?
What took you so long?
谢谢 福特老爷
Thank you, Master Ford.
普莱特
Platt.
太感谢了 福特老爷
My great thanks, Master Ford.
不 是我该谢你
No, my thanks to you.
这是你应得的
And it is the least of it.
希望这个能带给我们俩欢乐
I hope it brings us both much joy over the years.
天啊!
God!
艾来萨
Eliza.
别哭了!
Stop!
别再哭了!
Stop your wailing!
如果你就这样自暴自弃
If you let yourself be overcome
你会被毁了的
by sorrow, you will drown in it.
你不思念你的孩子们吗?
Have you stopped crying for your children?
虽然你不说 但是你能忘得了他们吗?
You make no sounds, but will you ever let them go in your heart?
他们可是我身上掉下来的肉
They are as my flesh.
谁不痛苦?
Then who is distressed?
我惹主人和夫人不高兴了?
Do I upset the master and the mistress?
难道他们的好心情比我心碎重要?
Do you care less about my loss than their well-being?
福特老爷是个好人
Master Ford is a decent man.
他是个奴隶主!
He is a slaver!
那是环境所迫
Under the circumstances.
就算是环境所迫 他也是个奴隶主
Under the circumstances, he is a slaver.
你对他卑躬屈膝
But you truckle at his boot.
对他逢迎讨好
You luxuriate in his favor.
我是为了生存!
I survive!
我不会自暴自弃!
I will not fall into despair!
我会向福特老爷贡献计策!
I will offer up my talents to Master Ford!
我要坚持到重获自由那一天!
I will keep myself hearty until freedom is opportune!
福特能给你自由?
Ford is your opportunity?
你以为他不知道你别有用心?
You think he does not know that you are more than you suggest?
但他什么也不帮你
But he does nothing for you.
什么也不
Nothing.
你和那些牲畜没什么两样
You are no better than prized livestock.
告诉他呀 告诉他!
Call for him. Call!
告诉他你以前的事情
Tell him of your previous circumstances,
看他会怎么做 所罗门
and see what it earns you, Solomon.
你就这样接受了普莱特这个身份?
So, you've settled into your role as Platt, then?
我的后背都是伤疤...
My back is thick with scars...
那都是自由的代价
for protesting my freedom.
不要责怪我
Do not accuse me.
我没责怪你 我没有
I accuse you of nothing. I cannot accuse.
为了生存 我也不得不屈服...
I have done dishonorable things to survive...
但是到头来 却还是落到这般田地
and for all of them, I have ended up here.
如果我勇敢地站出来 结果也不会更糟
No better than if I stood up for myself.
上帝 宽恕我吧
God, forgive me.
所罗门 让我为我的孩子哭一会吧!
Solomon, let me weep for my children!
"无论是谁 都要如同
"Whosoever, therefore, shall humble
婴孩般卑微...
himself as this little child...
平等是天堂里最重要的原则
the same is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven.
若有人得幸能够抚育我的孩子..."
And who so shall receive one such little child in my name..."
我体会不了那种忧愁
I cannot have that kind of depression about.
"若有人侵犯我的孩子...
"But who so shall offend one of these little ones...
他最好在脖子挂上石头...
it were better for him that a millstone were hanged about his neck...
然后深沉入大海之中"
and he were drowned in the depth of the sea."
阿门
Amen.
把它们弄光滑点
Make them boards flush.
已经很光滑了 先生
They are, sir.
不 不够光滑
No, they is no such thing.
他们就像小马的皮毛一样光滑
They are as smooth to the touch as a yearling's coat.
你是在说我说谎吗?
Are you calling me a liar, boy?
您误会我了 先生
It's all a matter of perspective, sir.
可能从你的角度看来会有所不同
From where you stand, you may see differently,
但是我的手艺不会有差的
but the hands are not mistaken.
我只希望您在下结论前要好好体会一下
I simply ask that you use all your senses before rendering judgment.
天啊 你真不知礼
Oh, my, you are a brute.
你这个狗崽子
You are a dog.
还很不守规矩!
And no better for following instruction!
我按命令做的
I do as ordered.
那你黎明就起床
Then you'll be up at daybreak.
从查平那里拿一桶钉子...
You will procure a keg of nails from Chapin...
开始钉护墙板
and commence to putting on clapboards.
遵命 先生
Yes, sir.
把它们弄光滑
Make them boards flush.
不要 求你了! 求你了 山姆!
No, please! Please, Sam!
你们要带我去哪? 要带我去哪 山姆?
Where am I going? Where am I going, Sam?
所罗门! 所罗门!
Solomon! Solomon!
所罗门!
Solomon!
我的主人很喜欢我 你懂的
When I say I had my Master's favor, you understand.
这九年来...
And for nine years...
他让我生活得丰衣足食
he blessed me with every comfort and luxury in life.
给我丝绸 首饰...
Silks and jewels...
甚至还有人伺候我们
and even servants to wait upon us.
这样的生活
Such was our life.
我为他生下了一双儿女
And the life of this beautiful girl I bore for him.
但贝瑞太太的女儿...
But Master Berry's daughter...
她一直都看我不顺眼
she always looked at me with an unkind nature.
她憎恨艾米丽 虽然她们是亲生姐妹
And she hated Emily, no matter she and Emily were flesh of flesh.
贝瑞太太的身体垮了
As Master Berry's health failed,
那个家就是她说的算...
she gained power of the household...
最后因为自由证的问题...
and eventually, I was brought to the city under the false pretense...
我被带到了城里
of our free papers being executed.
我可怜的孩子们
My poor children.
我不是告诉过你装上护墙板吗?
I thought I told you to commence to putting on clapboards.
我正在这么做 主人 这些已经换好了
Yes, Master, I'm about it. These have all been replaced.
我不是还说拿一桶钉子来吗?
And didn't I tell you to get a keg of nails?
我拿来了
And so, I did.
拿来了
So, you did.
该死的 你怎么什么都做不好!
God damn you. I thought you knowed something!
我按照您吩咐做的
I did as instructed.
如果我做错 那也是因为您吩咐错了
If there's something wrong, it's wrong with the instruction.
你这个黑鬼
You black bastard.
该死的黑鬼
You goddamn black bastard.
把衣服脱了
Strip your clothes.
脱了
Strip.
我不脱
I will not.
你活不过今天的 黑鬼!
You will not live to see another day, nigger!
救命啊!
Help!
杀人了!
Murder!
我错了!
I'm sorry!
我错了! 我错了!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
怎么回事?
What is the matter?
底比斯老爷因为我用了
Master Tibeats wants to whip me
您给我的钉子而要打我
for using the nails you gave me.
这事我跟你没完
This ain't done by half.
你会付出代价的
I will have flesh.
血的代价!
And I will have all of it!
别乱走动
Do not stir.
别离开庄园 因为出了这里我就没法保护你了
Do not leave the plantation. For, if you run, I cannot protect you.
待在这里
Stay here.
先生们 谁敢动这个黑奴我就跟他不客气
Gentlemen, whoever moves that nigger is a dead man.
我是这个农场的监工
I am the overseer on this plantation.
威廉・福特持有普莱特的所有权
William Ford holds the mortgage on Platt.
如果你们绞死他 福特先生会损失惨重的
If you hang him, he will lose his debt.
你们无权处置他的财产
You have no claim to his life.
还有你们俩...
As for you two...
要是还想继续活着的话...
if you have any regard for your own safety...
就快给我滚!
I say, be gone!
你没有权利!
You got no cause!
普莱特是我的人 我愿意怎么处置都行!
Platt is mine, and mine to do with as I please!
你要是敢动...
If you touch...
山姆!
Sam!
骑着骡子 去找福特老爷
Fetch the mule. Get Master Ford.
普莱特 可怜的普莱特
Platt. Poor Platt.
我想底比斯就潜伏在附近某处
I believe Tibeats is skulking about the premises somewhere.
他会想方设法地置你于死地
He wants you dead, and he will have it so.
这里很不安全
It's no longer safe for you here.
如果底比斯动手 你肯定会还手
And I don't believe you will remain passive if Tibeats attacks.
我把你转给了艾德文・艾普斯
I have transferred my debt to Edwin Epps.
他会负责你...
He will take charge...
福特老爷
Master Ford.
您一定要明白 我不是奴隶
You must know that I'm not a slave.
不要说这些
I cannot hear that.
来到你家之前 我是个自由人
Before I came to you, I was a freeman.
我这是在救你!
I'm trying to save your life!
我一直在为你操心
And I have a debt to be mindful of.
现在换成艾德文・艾普斯了
And that is to Edwin Epps now.
他不好对付 对黑奴心狠手辣
And he is a hard man. Prides himself on being a nigger breaker.
但我实在找不到别人愿意接受你
But truthfully, I could find no others who would take you.
你已经臭名远扬了
You've made a reputation of yourself.
不管在哪里 你都是一个特立独行的黑奴 普莱特
Whatever the circumstances, you are an exceptional nigger, Platt.
但这样对你没好处
But I fear no good will come of it.
"奴仆们要..."
"And that servant...
谨记主的意志..."
which knew his lord's will..."
谨记主的意志
Which knew his lord's will.
"毫不顾己..."
"And prepared not himself..."
毫不顾己
Prepared not himself.
"也不擅自行事..."
"Neither did according to his will..."
否则鞭刑不怠"
shall be beaten with many stripes."
明白了吗?
Do you hear that?
"鞭刑"
"Stripes."
若不服从主的意愿...
That nigger that don't obey his lord...
也就是服从主人 明白吗?
that's his master, do you see?
否则鞭刑不怠
That there nigger shall be beaten with many stripes.
这里的鞭刑指的是很多下
Now, "many" signifies a great many.
40下 100下 150下
40, 100, 150 lashes.
圣经里这么写的
That's scripture.
摘棉花
Pick that cotton.
动作快点
Move along, now.
快点 爱德华! 让那些黑奴快点!
Come on, Edward! Drive them niggers!
摘棉花! 动作快点
Pick that cotton! Move along, now.
磨蹭什么 小子? 快干!
What are you doing, boy? Come on!
鲍伯摘了240磅
240 for Bob.
詹姆斯多少?
What you got for James?
295磅
295 pounds.
干得不错 小子
That's real good, boy. That's real good.
普莱特摘了182磅
182 for Platt.
通常一个黑奴一天摘多少?
How much can even an average nigger pick a day?
200磅吧
200 pounds.
这个黑奴没达到标准
This nigger ain't even average.
派茜摘了512磅
512 pounds for Patsey.
512磅!
512!
派茜比你们多摘了那么多 你们不脸红吗?
You menfolk got no shame letting Patsey out-pick you.
她每天都能摘500多磅
The day ain't yet come she swung lower than 500 pounds.
她真是农场女王
Queen of the fields, she is.
138磅...
138 pounds...
我还没说完 特里奇
I ain't done, Treach.
我想表扬派茜一下 难道不行吗?
Ain't I owed a minute to luxuriate on the work Patsey done?
当然行 先生
Yes, sir.
农场女王
Damn queen.
天生的农场工人
Born and bred to the field.
黑奴中的佼佼者
A nigger among niggers.
上帝将她赐予我
And God gave her to me.
是我正直人生的回馈
A lesson in the rewards of righteous living.
显而易见
All be observant to that.
是的!
All!
好了 特里奇 继续说吧
Now, Treach. Now speak.
皮布摘了138磅
138 pounds for Phebe.
她昨天摘了145磅 把她拖出来
Hit 145 yesterday. Pull her out.
乔治摘了145磅
206 pounds for George.
他昨天摘了多少?
How much he pick yesterday?
229磅
229.
把他拖出来
Get him out.
快走
Come on, get.
快点走
Come on.
动作快点 小子!
Come on, boy, move!
起来!
Get up!
我们跳舞吧! 起来!
We dance tonight! Get up!
拿上小提琴 Platt 快起来!
Get your fiddle, Platt. Get up!
快点! 拿着 拿着!
Come on! Get, get, get!
快点 普莱特 快点!
Come on, Platt. Come on!
大家都高兴点! 跳起来吧!
Come on, where's your merriment? Move your feet!
卖了她
Sell her.
这是怎么回事?
What's all this?
你得把她卖掉
You will sell the negress.
卖掉小派茜?
Sell little Pats?
她比其他黑奴摘的棉花都多
She pick with more vigor than any other nigger.
卖另一个吧
Choose another to go.
不行
No other.
卖了她
Sell her.
我不卖
I will not.
你立刻把这个黑婊子卖掉...
You will remove that black bitch from this property...
否则我就回城里去
or I'll take myself back to Cheneyville.
回到你原来的那个猪圈里?
Back to that hog's trough where I found you?
不要跟派茜过不去 亲爱的
Do not set yourself up against Patsey, my dear.
因为我不会卖了她
Because I will rid myself of you
但我会甩了你
well before I do away with her.
看什么看?
What you looking at?
臭娘们
Damn woman.
我不会让她打扰我的雅兴
I won't have my mood spoiled.
不会的
I will not.
接着跳
Dance.
都给我跳起来!
Dance, I says!
跳起来!
Come on!
继续拉 普莱特 就拉这首
Pick it up, Platt. Play that fiddle, boy.
普莱特
Platt.
在 夫人?
Yes, Mistress?
你能找到去巴塞洛缪的杂货铺的路吗?
Can you find your way to Bartholomew's?
我可以 夫人
I can, ma'am.
这个单子上列了一些东西
This is a list of goods and sundries.
你把上面列的买完后马上回来
You will take it to be filled and return immediately.
带上你的奴隶牌
Take your tag.
告诉巴塞洛缪记在我们账上
Tell Bartholomew to add it to our debt.
是 夫人
Yes, Mistress.
你老家是哪的 普莱特?
Where you from, Platt?
我告诉过您
I told you.
再跟我说一遍
Tell me again.
华盛顿
Washington.
你以前的主人是谁?
Who were your master?
是弗里曼
Master name a Freeman.
他有文化吗?
Was he a learned man?
我想是的
I suppose so.
是他教你认的字?
He learn you to read?
一点点而已 他时不时就教教我
A word, here or there.
但我完全不会写...
But I have no understanding of the written...
别给自己找麻烦去学写字
Don't trouble yourself with it.
你和其他黑奴一样 你的主人买你回来仅仅是干活用的
Same as the rest. Master brought you here to work, that's all.
过了这个界限 小心鞭子伺候
Any more will earn you 100 lashes.
过来 小子
Come here, boy.
来啊
Come on.
你要去哪 小子?
Where you going, boy?
去巴塞洛缪的杂货铺
On my way to Bartholomew's.
艾普斯夫人让我去的
Sent by Mistress Epps.
那么 你最好是要去那里
You best get there, then.
动作要快
Get there quick.
路上有碰到麻烦吗?
Any trouble?
没有 夫人 一切顺利
No, ma'am. No trouble.
普莱特・艾普斯 周日早上好
Platt Epps, good Sunday morning.
早上好 肖老爷
Good morning, Master Shaw.
主人让我来找派茜 我能进去吗?
Master sent me to retrieve Patsey. May I approach?
可以
You may.
打扰您了 肖夫人
Excuse me, Mistress Shaw.
什么事 黑奴普莱特
Nigger Platt.
派茜 主人希望你现在回去
Patsey, Master wishes you to return.
今天是安息日 我是可以自由活动的
The Sabbath day, I is free to roam.
老爷让我跑过来找你 他说不能浪费一分一秒
Master sent me running to fetch you, said no time should be wasted.
坐下喝杯茶吧?
Drink of tea?
谢谢 夫人 但我不敢
Thank you, Mistress, but I don't dare.
即使你准时回去了
Would you know of Master Epps's consternation
艾普斯老爷就会变得稍微温柔一点吗?
to be any lessened with your timely return?
他常年处在生气的状态
Anger's his constant condition.
坐下
Sit.
坐下 喝点茶 算我赏的
Sit and drink the tea that I offered.
艾普斯在担心什么?
What'n be Epps's concern?
我还是不说的好
I'd rather not say.
安息日来点小八卦不碍事的 适量来点就好
Oh, little gossip on the Sabbath be fine. All things in moderation.
您也知道...
As you are aware...
艾普斯老爷总是不苟言笑
Master Epps is a man of hard countenance.
您也知道他不喜欢您丈夫
You know he has ill feeling towards your husband.
他确实不喜欢
He do.
艾普斯老爷不知怎么的 认为...
Master Epps has somehow come to believe...
肖老爷是个色狼
that Master Shaw is something of a lothario.
这肯定是搞错了 毫无疑问的
A misguided belief, no doubt.
毫无疑问...
No doubt...
空穴来风 未必无因
if not born out of truth itself.
我没有冒犯的意思
I meant no disrespect.
他没听到你的话
He ain't heard you.
我也没有冒犯您的意思 夫人
I meant no disrespect to you, Mistress.
没必要担心我的感受
Got no cause to worry for my sensibilities.
我都不记得鞭子是什么滋味了
I ain't felt the end of a lash in more years I can recall.
我也从没干过粗活
I ain't worked a field, neither.
我曾服侍过别人...
Where once I served...
但现在 是别人来服侍我了
now, I have others serving me.
这是我现在地位的代价...
The cost to my current existence...
肖老爷到处宣扬他对我的爱的代价...
be Master Shaw broadcasting his affections...
还有我享受他好丈夫表演的代价
and me enjoying the pantomime of his fidelity.
如果这些能让我远离摘棉花的黑奴生活 就这样继续吧
If that what keep me from cotton picking niggers, that what it be.
这个代价很小 也很合理
A small and reasonable price to be paid, for sure.
我知道成为老爷的意中人
I know what it like to be the object
和心仪对象的感觉
of Master's predilections and peculiarities.
一到晚上 等待你的不是被侵犯...
A lusty visit in the night...
就是被毒打
or a visitation with the whip.
别担心 派茜
Take comfort, Patsey.
伟大的主会修理艾普斯的
The good Lord will manage Epps.
在最后审判的时刻 伟大的主会修理他们所有人的
In his own time, the good Lord will manage them all.
法老的诅咒就是那些...
The curse of the pharaohs were a poor example...
种植园主的悲惨下场
of what wait for the plantation class.
现在很不错
This is nice.
小茜 派茜!
Pats. Patsey!
别朝他那个方向看 继续走
Do not look in his direction. Continue on.
- 派茜!  - 找到她了 主人
- Patsey!  - Found her, Master.
我也把她带回来了 按照您吩咐的那样
And brought her back, just as instructed.
你刚才跟她说了什么?
What did you just now tell her?
你刚才对小茜说了什么?
What did you say to Pats?
一个字都没说 什么都没有
No words were spoken, none of consequence.
你是个骗子
You're a liar.
你他妈是个骗子
You damn liar.
我看到你跟她说话了
I saw you talking with her.
告诉我
Tell me.
我说不出我根本没说过的话
I cannot speak of what did not occur.
我要割断你那黑黢黢的脖子!
I'll cut your black throat!
主人!
Master!
你过来
You come here.
- 艾普斯老爷  - 我说 过来!
- Master Epps.  - I said come here!
我把她带回来了 按照您...
I brought her back, just like you...
- 过来!  - 主人!
- Come here!  - Master!
主人
Master.
我找到了她 按照您吩咐的那样
I got her, just as instructed.
艾普斯老爷!
Master Epps!
你离小茜远一点 兔崽子
You stay away from Pats, boy.
艾普斯老爷
Master Epps.
今天是安息日
It's the Lord's day.
哪有基督徒是像我们这样的
Ain't nothing Christian in us carrying on like this.
你赢了
I concede to you.
勇敢一点...
In the name of valor...
扶你的主人起来
help your master to his feet.
我要宰了你!
I'm gonna kill you!
怎么回事?
What's the fuss?
艾普斯老爷以为派茜和我在说话
Master Epps believed Patsey and me
但我们根本没有
to be in conversation when we were not.
我想解释 但最后就变成了这样
I tried to explain, but it's led to all this.
这是怎么回事?
What is it?
你见不着她连安息日都过不下去了?
You can't remain the Sabbath without her under your eye?
你就是个没种的混蛋
You are a no-account bastard.
肮脏的 目中无神的蛮子
A filthy, godless heathen.
我的床对你而言太过神圣了
My bed is too holy for you to share.
他都告诉你了什么?
What's he been telling you?
你的那些无耻行径
Of your misbegotten ways.
他都知道些什么?
And he would know what of anything?
我今天都还没和他说过话
I ain't even spoken with him today.
你个满嘴谎言的黑鬼 普莱特
You lying nigger, Platt.
我有吗?
Have I?
看 那就是他所谓的真相
There. There's all the truth he got.
该死的黑鬼
Damn nigger.
派茜
Patsey.
舞会的休息时间到了
A moment from the dancing.
看看我给你们都准备了什么
Come sample what I baked for y'all.
谢谢 夫人
Thank you, Mistress.
没你的份 派茜
There will be none for you, Patsey.
你看到了吗?
You see that?
你看到她对我那傲慢的表情了吗?
You see that look of insolence she give me?
除了她转过身去 我什么都没看到
I seen nothing but her turn away.
你是真瞎了还是故意的?
Are you blind or ignorant?
那是毒辣辣的 充满仇恨的蔑视
It was hot, hateful scorn.
都写在那张黢黑的脸上
It filled that black face.
你告诉我你没看到...
You tell me you didn't see it...
要么是因为你选择视而不见 要么你的意思是我在说谎?
it's because you choose not to look, or are you saying I lie?
不管是哪种 都已经过去了
Whatever it was, it passed.
你就是这么对黑鬼的?
Is that how you are with the niggers?
让每一丝邪恶的想法都在他们内心疯狂滋生?
Letting every ill thought fester inside them?
看看他们
Look at them.
他们心里满满都是
They foul with it.
满满都是仇恨的种子
They foul with their hate.
你如果放任不管 他们就会在夜晚来报复我们
You let it be, it's gonna come back to us in the dark of night.
你想要这样的结果?
You want that?
你想让这些黑鬼趁我们熟睡的时候宰了我们
You want them black animals leave us
然后内脏流的到处都是?
gut like pigs in our own sleep?
哦...
Oh...
你真不是个爷们
You are manless.
即便你是个男的 也是个阉货
A damn eunuch if there ever was.
即便你不同意我的话 我想你至少也该
If you won't stand for me, I pray you'd
证明自己是个爷们
at least be a credit to your own kind
把他们揍得服服帖帖的
and beat every foul thought from them.
把他们揍得服服帖帖的!
Beat it from them!
吃吧
Eat.
吃饱了
Fill yourselves.
然后继续跳舞
And then we dance.
听见没有 吃啊
I said, eat.
普莱特
Platt.
普莱特 你醒着吗?
Platt, you awake?
我醒着
I am.
我有个请求
I have a request.
希望你能好心帮帮我
An act of kindness.
这是我从夫人那里偷来的
I secreted it from the mistress.
还回去
Return it.
它是你的了 普莱特
It yours, Platt.
为什么?
For what cause?
满足我的唯一请求 杀了我吧
All I ask, end my life.
把我带到沼泽边缘
Take my body to the margin of the swamp.
掐住我的脖子 把我按在水里...
Take me by the throat, hold me low in the water...
直到我一动不动 死透了
until I is still and without life.
把我埋在一个孤独的地方
Bury me in a lonely place of dying.
我不会做这种事的
I will do no such thing.
你刚才说的那些血淋淋的细节...
The gory detail with which you speak...
我已经仔细想了很久很久
I thought on it long and hard.
这只不过是忧郁症
It is melancholia.
不是别的
Nothing more.
你怎么会这么绝望?
How can you fall into such despair?
你怎么会不知道?
How can you not know?
我的生活一点都不快乐
I ain't got no comfort in this life.
如果你不能看在钱的份上帮我...
If I can't buy mercy from you...
那我只能求你了
I'll beg it.
还有别人
There are others.
- 去求他们吧  - 我在求你
- Beg them.  - I'm begging you.
为什么?
Why?
为什么你要我来做这件天理不容的事?
Why would you consign me to damnation with such an ungodly request?
上帝就在这里!
There is God here!
上帝是仁慈的...
God is merciful...
他也会原谅仁慈的行为
and he forgive merciful acts.
你不会下地狱的
Won't be no hell for you.
杀了我吧
Do it.
替我完成这件我没有勇气去自己完成的事
Do what I ain't got the strength to do myself.
这是瘟疫
It's a plague.
是棉铃虫而已
It's cotton worm.
这就是瘟疫 这是该死的圣经给我的指示
It's a plague. It's damn biblical.
两季了 上帝降下瘟疫来毁灭我
Two seasons God done sent a plague to smite me.
我做了什么让上帝如此恨我?
What I done that God hates me so?
这就是目无上帝的人的命运
It's that godless lot.
是他们把瘟疫带来的
They brought this on me.
我带给他们上帝的福音
I bring them God's word and heathens
而这些异教徒 却把上帝的诅咒带给我
they are, they brung me God's scorn.
该死的!
Damn!
你个该死的!
Damn you!
你们所有人都该死!
Damn all y'all!
法官阁下
Judge.
艾普斯老爷
Mister Epps.
听到您不幸的消息 我深表遗憾
I am deeply saddened to hear about your misfortune.
但我没从您出的价钱里看到您的遗憾
Your price don't reflect your concern.
听着
Listen up.
这一季 你们归特纳法官
You're Judge Turner's for the season.
如果有必要的话 你们还得呆得更久 直到我的棉花继续开始长
More, if need be, until my crops return.
你们别给我丢脸
Y'all bring no disrespect to me.
别把圣经里的瘟疫带给他 听到了吗?
Don't bring no biblical plagues to him, you hear?
否则 我就会扒了你们的皮
Or I'll take it out on your skin.
下来
Get out.
从门廊上下去 这不是你站的地方
Get off the porch. You ain't supposed to be on the porch.
快下去
Get off the porch.
普莱特 是吗?
Platt, is it?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
你以前种过甘蔗?
You cultivate cane previously?
没有 先生 我没种过
No, sir, I have not.
你的动作很纯熟
It comes to you quite naturally.
你受过教育?
Are you educated?
没有 先生 黑奴是来干活的 不是来读书写字的
No, sir. Niggers are hired to work, not read or write.
你会拉小提琴
You play the fiddle.
是的 先生 我会拉
Yes, sir. Yes, I do.
威拉德・亚纳 河上游的一个种植园主...
Willard Yarner, a planter up the bayou...
三周后要庆祝他的结婚纪念日
celebrates his anniversary in three weeks' time.
我会把你的名字报给他
I'll hold out your name to him.
你赚的就自己收着吧
What you earn is yours to keep.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
小心点 普莱特
Mind yourself, Platt.
安妮 玛格丽特 阿朗佐
呜哇!
Whoa!
多快乐的日子
Joyous day.
黑暗的日子已经远去
Dark times is behind us.
严谨地生活和真诚地祈祷真的把瘟疫赶走了!
Clean living and prayer done lifted the plague!
棉花就像新英格兰的雪一样又厚又白
As thick and white as New England snow.
现在 我的黑奴们回来了
Now, my niggers is returned to me.
听说特纳法官给了你点好处
Heard Judge Turner gave you favor.
普莱特 你是不是把他也骗了 用你惯用的伎俩?
Did you beguile him, Platt, with your slick nigger ways?
小子 在我的地盘
You won't stand idle, boy.
你不会有这闲工夫的
Not on my land.
活多得干不完!
Much work to do!
日子又开始变得漫长 对吗?
Days of old long since, huh?
开心吧
Joyous.
很开心吧 肯定的! 呜哇!
Joyous, indeed! Whoo!
我们去给你找点甜点吧 怎么样?
Let's go find something sweet for you. Hmm?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
糖果
Candy.
想吃糖果?
Candy?
# 噢 摘棉花 #
# Oh, pick this cotton #
# 摘棉花 #
# Pick this cotton #
# 噢 摘棉花 #
# Oh, pick this cotton #
# Oh, pick that cotton #
# 主人一点都不吝啬 伙计们 #
# Man ain't mean, boys #
# 主人一点都不吝啬 #
# Man ain't mean #
# 噢 摘棉花 #
# Oh, work this cotton #
# 摘棉花 #
# Work this cotton #
# 噢 摘棉花 #
# Oh, work this cotton #
# 摘棉花 #
# Work this cotton #
# 噢 干活一点都不累 伙计们 #
# Oh, work ain't hard, boys #
乔治
George.
摘了180磅
180 pounds.
派茜
Patsey.
派茜摘了520磅
520 pounds for Patsey.
好姑娘 从不让我失望
That's my girl. Don't ever let me down.
普莱特呢?
Platt?
160磅
160 pounds.
阿姆斯比?
Armsby?
64磅
64 pounds.
干得好的话 平均下来每人能摘200磅
A good day's labor would average 200 pounds.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
我相信过不了多久 你就会上手的
I'm sure in time, you'll develop as a picker.
但这需要努力
But it takes effort, boy.
用点心
Put some damn effort into it.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
带他们出去 挨鞭子吧
Take them out, get to whipping.
真是个悲剧
It's a tragedy.
这一切怎么会发生?
How does such come to pass?
卑贱地在地里干活 采摘棉花
Working a field and picking cotton like a lowly hand.
我的地位也就高那么一点点
I'm of a damn sight better station.
你知道 我是个监工
I worked as an overseer, you know.
我不知道 先生
I did not know, sir.
别用"先生"
Not "sir."
喊我"阿姆斯比"
Just "Armsby."
我欠他的 不比你们中的任何一人多
I'm not owed more than any other in the field.
那你怎么会来这里的 如果你不介意我这么问?
How did you arrive at such a place, if I may ask?
别这么正式 我们只是聊聊天而已
Ask, it's just conversation.
我那会有点嗜酒...
I became a little too dependent on the whiskey...
对工作很不上心
a little too undependable on the job.
听着 在你骂我酒鬼之前...
Now, before you say I'm just a sorry drunkard...
让我把话讲完
let me state my case.
像监工这种稳定的活
As reliable employment as overseeing is,
其实是对精神上的折磨
it is no easy chore on the spirit.
我的意思是 任何一个有良知的人...
I say, no man of conscious...
都会因天天抽打他人...
can take the lash to another human day in and day out...
使得自己内心饱受折磨
without shredding at his own self.
时间久了...
Takes him to a place...
他要么为了保持心智 不断为自己找借口...
where he either makes excuses within his mind to be unaffected...
要么寻求某种方式惩罚自己的罪孽
or he finds some way to trample his guilty sensations.
所以 我选择惩罚自己
So, I trampled.
不断地惩罚
With frequency.
我沉迷于财富的传说
I gave in to tales of wealth and prosperity.
但高额的利润却都涌进种植园主人们的口袋里
But such profitable outcomes are reserved for plantation masters.
而我们其余的人只能任劳任怨
It's the lot of the rest of us to serve.
现在 我只想拿份体面地收入然后回家
Now, all I want is to earn a decent wage and get myself home.
我日复一日的劳作
The proceeds of my fiddling performances.
只挣了这么一点 但这是我的所有了
Just a few picayunes, but all I have in the world.
如果你能帮帮我 我就把这些全部都给你
I promise them to you if you will do me the favor I require.
但我请求你 如果你做不到 不要把我供出来
But I beg you not to expose me if you cannot grant the request.
嗯...
Uh...
你想要我做什么?
What is it you ask?
首先 你得保证 先生
First, your word, sir.
我以我的名誉担保
On my honor.
我的请求很简单
It's a simple enough request.
我只需要你去一趟马克思维的邮局
I only ask that you deposit a letter
帮我寄一封信...
at the post office in Marksville...
然后永远保守这个秘密
and that you keep the action an inviolable secret forever.
先生 请庇护我
A patron is what I require, sir.
我会的
I'll do it.
我会接受你给我的报酬 无论多少
And I'll accept whatever payment's offered.
为了帮你 我让自己陷于危险之中
To assist you, I put my own self at risk.
但我还会这么做...
I will do so...
只要求有些合理的补偿
but fair compensation is all I ask.
写好你的信
Draw up your letter.
我们两天后见?
We'll meet again in two days?
好 两天后
In two days.
谢谢
Thank you.
听着 伙计...
Well, boy...
我听说我有个识字的黑奴 他不但会写信
I understand I got a learned nigger that writes letters.
还想找个白人帮他寄信来着
Tries to get white fellas to mail them.
阿姆斯比今天告诉我的...
Armsby told me today...
魔鬼在我的黑奴中作祟
the devil was among my niggers.
我尤其需要盯着其中的某位...
That I had one that needed watching...
不然他就会逃跑
or he would run away.
我问他为什么...
When I asked him why...
他告诉我你去找他...
he said you come over to him...
半夜把他叫醒...
waked him up in the middle of the night...
求他去马克思维那边...
and wanted him to carry a letter...
帮你寄封信
to Marksville.
你有什么想说的?
What do you got to say to that?
这不是真的
There's no truth to it.
你接着说
You say.
没有纸和墨水 我怎么写信?
How could I write a letter without ink or paper?
我给谁写信? 据我所知 我在这世上的朋友所剩无几了
Who am I gonna write to? I got no friends living as I know of.
那个叫阿姆斯比的家伙...
That Armsby...
他是个谎话连篇的酒鬼
That Armsby is a lying, drunken fellow.
他是不是想让你雇他做监工?
Didn't he want you to hire him as an overseer?
这就说得清了
Well, that's it.
他想让你相信我们都会逃跑...
He wants to make you believe we're all gonna run away...
这样你就会雇佣他
so you'll hire him as an overseer.
他觉得你是个偏听偏信的人
He believes you're a soft soap.
所以他才会瞎编乱造
And he's given to such talk.
凭空捏造一个故事...
Made this story out of whole cloth...
为了达到自己的目的
because he wants a situation.
主人 这全是假的
It's all a lie, Master.
都是谎话
It's all a lie.
真见鬼
I'll be damned.
普莱特 要不是因为他是个自由的白人
Were he not free and white, Platt.
自由的白人
Were he not free and white.
# 太阳会在这里落山 #
# Sun gonna set here #
# 在山那边 #
# Under the mountain #
# 太阳会在这里落山 #
# Sun gonna set here #
# 在山那边 #
# Under the mountain #
# 太阳会在这里落山 #
# Sun gonna set here #
# 在山那边 #
# Under the mountain #
爱德华!
Edward!
往他身上浇点水
Get him water.
快起来!
Get up!
快起来
黑鬼 起来!
Nigger, get up!
伙计 你看什么呢?
What you looking at, boy?
继续干活 伙计!
Keep picking, boy!
我想说点关于艾布拉姆叔叔的事
I just wanna say something about Uncle Abram.
他是个好人...
He was a good man...
自从我们很小的时候 他就经常照顾我们
and he always looked out for us ever since we were little.
愿上帝爱他
God love him.
保佑他 关照他
God bless him. God keep him.
阿门
Amen.
# 去约旦河吧 #
# Went down to the River Jordan #
# 在那里 约翰曾为三个人施洗 #
# Where John baptized three #
# 当我唤醒来自地狱的恶魔时 #
# When I woke the devil in hell #
# 我告诉他是约翰为我施洗的 #
# Said Johnny baptized me #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# I said roll, Jordan, roll #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 有些人说约翰是施洗者 #
# Well, some say John was a Baptist #
# 有些人说约翰是犹太人 #
# Some say John was a Jew #
# 但我说约翰是一名牧师 #
# But I say John was a preacher #
# 因为圣经上也这么写着的 #
# 'Cause my Bible says so too #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# I said roll, Jordan, roll #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 哈利路亚 #
# Hallelujah #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 哈利路亚 #
# Hallelujah #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 大家一起唱 #
# Everybody say #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 噢 孩子们 #
# Oh, children #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 哈利路亚 #
# Hallelujah #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
放到最边上
Right to the end.
嘿 巴斯
Hey, Bass.
噢 不用了 不了
Oh, no, no, no.
大热天的休息会儿没什么
No shame in taking respite from the heat.
喝点酒 乘会凉
Drink, shade.
对旅行者来说有点大逆不道 对朋友来讲就要另当别论了
It's ungodly for travelers, hearty or otherwise.
笑什么?
What's funny?
艾普斯 我只是想按要求把手上的活干完
Epps, I merely mean to finish the work at hand, as requested.
获得酬劳
And as paid for.
如果有什么让你觉得不舒服...
If something rubs you wrongly...
我给你个机会说出来
I offer you the opportunity to speak on it.
你既然问了 那我不妨直说吧
You ask plainly, so I will tell you plainly.
我觉得好笑的是 大热天的 您只顾关心我的身体状况...
What amused me just then was your concern for my well-being in this heat...
而同时 坦白的说 您工人的状况...
when, quite frankly, the condition of your laborers...
"我工人的状况"?
"The condition of my laborers"?
他们的状况很糟糕 糟透了
It is horrid. It's all wrong.
糟透了 艾普斯先生
All wrong, Mr. Epps.
他们不是雇来帮忙的
They ain't hired help.
他们是我的资产
They're my property.
你的语气很骄傲
You say that with pride.
我说的是事实
I say it as fact.
如果非要聊聊哪些是事实
If this conversation concerns what is factual
哪些不是 那么我觉得我有必要说出来...
and what is not, then it must be said...
对于奴隶来说 没什么公平或者权利可言
that there is no justice nor righteousness in their slavery.
不过你确实提出了一个很有意思的问题
But you do open up an interesting question.
如果把问题归结为一点
What right have you to your niggers,
你究竟对你的黑奴们有什么权利呢?
when you come down to the point?
- 什么权利?  - 嗯
- What right?  - Mmm.
我买下他们 花钱买的
I bought them. I paid for them.
一点没错 而且法律明确规定
Of course you did, and the law says
你有权拥有黑奴
you have the right to hold a nigger.
恕我对法律的不敬 它说谎了
But begging the law's pardon, it lies.
如果颁布一条法令 剥夺你的自由
Suppose they pass a law taking away
让你成为奴隶
your liberty, making you a slave.
我是说如果
Suppose.
这种事不可能发生
That ain't a supposable case.
法律是会变的 艾普斯
Laws change, Epps.
普遍的真理才是永恒的
Universal truths are constant.
这是个事实 一个直白而简单的事实...
It is a fact, a plain and simple fact...
真相和权利对所有人来说都是一样的
that what is true and right is true and right for all.
对黑人和白人都是一样的
White and black alike.
巴斯 你拿我和黑鬼比?
You comparing me to a nigger, Bass?
我只是问问 在上帝眼里 我们和他们又有什么区别呢?
I'm only asking, in the eyes of God, what is the difference?
你也可以问问
You might as well ask what the difference is
白人和狒狒有什么区别
between a white man and a baboon.
我在奥尔良见过这种小动物
I seen one of them critters in Orleans.
他们懂得就和我的黑奴们一样多
Know just as much as any nigger I got.
听着 艾普斯
Listen, Epps.
这些黑奴们是人
These niggers are human beings.
如果他们无权活得比野蛮的动物好...
If they are allowed to climb no higher than brute animals...
你和像你一样的奴隶主们要为此负责
you and men like you will have to answer for it.
这是一种病态的社会现象 艾普斯先生...
There is an ill, Mr. Epps...
国内非常恐怖的病态现象
a fearful ill resting upon this nation.
早晚有一天这个国家会觉醒的
And there will be a day of reckoning yet.
巴斯 你比我认识的任何人...
You like to hear yourself talk, Bass...
更喜欢闭门造车
better than any man I know of.
如果有人要否定你...
You'd argue that black was white, or white, black...
你就会辩论说什么黑人白人都是一样的
if anybody would contradict you.
当然如果你住在美国东北部会很好多
A fine supposition if you lived among Yankees in New England.
可你不住那边
But you don't.
你肯定也去不了
You most assuredly do not.
我就知道 我就知道!
I knew it, I knew it, I knew it!
派茜!
Patsey!
小茜!
Pats!
她人呢?
Where is she?
小茜去哪了?
Where's Pats?
她在哪 该死的? 她人呢?
Where is she, damn it? Where is she?
菲比 她在哪? 派茜去哪了? 她在哪?
Phebs, where is she? Where is Patsey? Where is she?
你站在那里干什么?
What you standing there for?
我们对她一无所知 主人
We know nothing of her, Master.
- 对什么一无所知?  - 我们什么都不知道...
- Know nothing of what?  - We know nothing of...
不知道什么? 她去哪了?
Of what? Where has she gone?
她逃跑了 是吗?
She run off, ain't she?
我不知道 主人
I don't know, Master.
- 她在哪?  - 我不知道 主人
- Where is she?  - I don't know, Master.
你知道 你知道!
You know, you know, you know!
你知道!
You know!
不 我不知道!
No, I don't!
你们这些可怜的黑狗
You miserable black dogs.
你们个个都像是又聋又哑似的站在那儿
You stand like the deaf and dumb.
说话!
Speak!
她走了
She gone.
我的小茜走了
My Pats is gone.
逃跑? 你逃跑了 对吗?
Run off? Run off, did you?
- 艾普斯老爷...  - 你这个可怜的姑娘 你去哪了?
- Master Epps...  - You miserable wench. Where you been?
我哪也没去!
I been nowhere!
证据确凿你还不承认!
Lies to your misdeeds!
今天是安息日 老爷 我去
The Sabbath day, Master. I took me
散步了 去和上帝谈心了
a walk to commune with the Lord.
还把上帝扯进你的鬼话?
Bring the Lord into your deceptions?
你是从肖的种植园过来的
You're coming from Shaw's plantation.
- 不!  - 艾普斯老爷
- No!  - Master Epps.
现在你想说话了?
Now, you speak?
现在你想和她一起说谎 你知道开口了!
Now that you want to add to her lies, you find your tongue!
我去了肖老爷的种植园
I went to Master Shaw's plantation.
啊! 你承认了
Ah! You admit it.
是的 我承认
Yes, freely.
但你知道为什么吗?
And you know why?
我从肖夫人那得到了这个
I got this from Mistress Shaw.
艾普斯夫人甚至不会给我一块肥皂让我用来清洁
Mistress Epps won't even grant me no soap to clean with.
我太臭了 我自己都忍不住想吐!
I stink so much, I make myself gag!
500磅的棉花
500 pounds of cotton.
日复一日!
Day in, day out!
比这的任何一个男人都多
More than any man here.
有了这个 我会变得干净
And for that, I will be clean.
这就是我唯一的要求
That's all I ask.
我会去肖老爷的种植园就是为了这个
This, here, what I went to Shaw's for.
骗子
Liar.
上帝见证 真的是这样!
The Lord knows that's all!
你是个骗子
You're a liar.
而你 被你自己的贪婪蒙蔽!
And you, blind with your own covetousness!
我没有说谎 主人
I don't lie, Master.
如果你要杀了我 我也会坚持这么说
If you kill me, I'll stick to that.
看来我得好好教训你一顿
I'll fetch you down.
让你知道去肖那里的下场
I'll learn you to go to Shaw's.
特里奇
Treach.
去取绳子来
Run and fetch some line.
爱德华!
Edward!
把她衣服扒了 绑到树桩上给我狠狠地打
Strip her. Strike her bare and lash her to the post.
这是你自找的 小茜
You done this to yourself, Pats.
打啊
Do it.
把她往死里打
Strike the life from her.
你来打
Beat her.
让她尝尝鞭子的味道! 让她如愿以偿!
Give her the whip! Give it all to her!
普莱特 你过来 现在你来打她
Platt, you come here and you beat her now.
普莱特!
Platt!
过来!
Come here!
我宁愿由你来打 普莱特!
I'd rather it you, Platt!
你来打她
You strike her.
打她啊
Strike her.
他就没用劲
He pantomimes.
她身上几乎没有鞭痕
There's barely a welt on her.
这就是你的黑鬼...
That's what your niggers make of you...
把你当傻子一样愚弄
a fool for the taking.
打她 普莱特 打她啊!
Strike her, Platt. Strike her!
你给我好好地打
You will strike her.
你要打得她皮开肉绽
You will strike her until her flesh
血肉模糊...
is rent and meat and blood flow equal...
否则我看见一个黑奴 就杀一个
or I will kill every nigger in my sight.
你听懂了吗?
You understand me?
打她! 打她!
Strike her! Strike her!
我还没喊停呢 我说停你才能停!
Until I say no more. I ain't said nothing!
把鞭子给我!
Give me the whip!
起来!
Get up!
你这个魔鬼!
Thou devil!
总有一天...
Sooner or later...
善有善报 恶有恶报
somewhere in the course of eternal
总有一天你会遭报应的!
justice, thou shalt answer for this sin!
报应? 根本不会有报应
Sin? There is no sin.
人可以对他的财产为所欲为
Man does how he pleases with his property.
现在 普莱特 我现在心情已经很嗨
At the moment, Platt, I'm of great pleasure.
你他妈给我小心点
You be goddamn careful I don't want to
别再火上浇油
come and lighten my mood no further.
巴斯老爷
Master Bass.
请问您来自这个国家的哪个地方
I want to ask you what part of the country you come from.
我不是这个国家的
No part of this land.
我来自加拿大
I originate from Canada.
来 猜猜它在哪里
Now, guess where that is.
我知道加拿大在哪
I know where Canada is.
我自己去过那儿
I've been there myself.
蒙特利尔...
Montreal...
金斯顿 昆士顿 还有很多的地方
and Kingston and Queenston and a great many places.
对一个黑奴来说算阅历丰富了
Well-traveled for a slave.
你怎么来这的?
How came you here?
巴斯老爷...
Master Bass...
如果正义能够得以伸张 我怎么会到这来
if justice had been done, I never would have been here.
此话怎讲?
How's this?
告诉我
Tell me all.
我不敢告诉您
I'm afraid to tell you.
你所说的每一个字都会被严格保密
Every word you speak is a profound secret.
你的故事...
Your story...
真令人大吃一惊
it is amazing.
却很可悲
And in no good way.
您相信正义吗 先生 就像您所说的?
Do you believe, sir, in justice, as you said?
相信
I do.
您相信奴隶制是邪恶的并且应被彻底废除吗?
That slavery is an evil that should befall none?
我认为是的
I believe so.
若你真是如此...
If you truly do...
那么我请求你 我恳求你...
then I ask, I beg...
写封信给我在北方的朋友...
that you write my friends in the north...
让他们了解到我的处境...
acquainting them of my situation...
并且恳求他们证明我是自由的身份
and beseeching them to forward free papers.
重新见到我的妻子...
It would be...
和我的家人...
an unspeakable happiness...
那将是...
to see my wife...
无法言表的幸福
and my family again.
我来到这个国家20年了...
I traveled this country for the best part of 20 years...
我的自由就是一切
and my freedom is everything.
明天能离开这里 是我最高兴的事情
The fact that I can walk out of here tomorrow brings me great pleasure.
我的命对任何人都没有多大意义
My life doesn't mean much to anyone.
但看起来你的命对许多人都意义重大
It seems yours might mean a lot to a whole lot of people.
但是你的请求 令我害怕
But what you ask of me, sir, scares me.
我不得不说 我害怕
And I must say, I am afraid.
不仅仅是为你 还是为我
Not just for you, but for me.
我会为你写信的 先生
I will write your letter, sir.
而且如果它能为你带来自由
And if it brings you your freedom,
那不仅仅会是我的荣幸
it will be more than a pleasure.
那将会是我的责任
It will have been my duty.
现在 你可以把那些木片递给我吗?
Now, would you kindly hand me those shingles?
普莱特!
Platt!
叫普莱特的家伙在哪?
Where's the boy called Platt?
过来
Come here, boy.
你叫普莱特 对吗?
Your name is Platt, is it?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
你认识那个人吗?
You know that man?
帕克先生
Mr. Parker.
再说一遍?
Say again?
帕克先生
Mr. Parker.
那位先生收到了一封充满着许多指控的信
That man received a letter compiling many accusations.
你看着我的眼睛...
You look me in the eye...
并且无论如何 请你如实地回答我
and on your life, you answer me truthfully.
除了普莱特你还有其他名字吗?
Have you any other name than Platt?
所罗门・诺瑟普是我的名字
Solomon Northup is my name.
治安官 这是怎么回事?
Sheriff, what's all this?
这是公事
It's official business.
我的黑奴 就是我的事
My nigger, my business.
你的事可以等
Your business waits.
跟我说说你的家庭
Tell me of your family.
我有一位妻子 两个孩子
I have a wife, two children.
这他妈什么情况?
What the hell?
- 你孩子的姓名?  - 玛格丽特和阿朗佐
- What are your children's names?  - Margaret and Alonzo.
你妻子结婚前叫什么?
What was your wife's name before her marriage?
叫安妮・汉普顿 我就是你们要找的人
Anne Hampton. I am who I say.
你去哪 普莱特?
Where you going, Platt?
谁授权你干涉我的财产了?
Who authorized you to interfere with my property?
这是我的权力
My authority.
普莱特 你回来 普莱特!
Platt, you come back here. Platt!
小子 你回来
You come back here, boy.
孩子
Boy.
你放开他 普莱特是我的黑奴!
You unhand him. Platt is my nigger!
他是所罗门・诺瑟普先生
He is Mr. Solomon Northup.
你瞎说
You say.
你到这儿来 和我不熟 还要来抢我的人
You come here, unfamiliar to me, and make claims.
毫无疑问 这位先生就是所罗门・诺瑟普
I got no doubts. The man is Solomon Northup.
他是个鬼! 他是我的黑奴 我会为他跟你死磕到底!
The hell he is! He's my nigger, and I'll fight you for him!
你有你的权利
As is your right.
我也有我的权利 而且我也很乐意在法庭上让你倾家荡产
As it will be my pleasure to bankrupt you in the courts.
你自己决定 放开他
Your decision. Unhand him.
我知道这件事你也有份 普莱特
I know you had some hand in this, Platt.
我会弄个水落石出的
I'm gonna get to the bottom of it.
别理他
Pay him no mind.
我为这个黑奴付了大价钱
I paid good money for this nigger.
法院的文件可以证明这一点!
Courthouse got papers to prove it!
我们也有文件证明他是自由的!
And we got papers proving he's free!
你是我的 你是属于我的 你听见了吗 普莱特?
I own you. You belong to me. You hear me, Platt?
放开他!
Unhand him!
日落之前 你的背上会再添200个伤口的!
You'll have 200 stripes across your back by sundown!
普莱特!
Platt!
把我的马牵来 特里奇
Get my horse, Treach.
离他远点 小茜
Get away from him, Pats.
我很快就会见到你的
I'm gonna be seeing you real soon.
所罗门 我们得快点
Solomon, we need to make haste.
不
No.
快 所罗门
Solomon.
我会道歉...
I'll apologize...
为我的出现道歉
for my appearance.
但过去的这些年里...
But I have had...
我经历了...
a difficult time...
一段艰难的岁月
these past several years.
玛格丽特
Margaret.
阿朗佐
Alonzo.
他是谁?
Who is this?
他是我的丈夫
He's my husband.
丈夫
Husband.
很高兴见到你 先生
It is very good to meet you, sir.
我们还有很多需要互相了解
We have much acquainting to do.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
然后这是你的外孙
And this is your grandson.
他叫所罗门・诺瑟普・斯汤顿
Solomon Northup Staunton.
所罗门
Solomon.
安妮...
Anne...
原谅我
forgive me.
没有什么要原谅的
There is nothing to forgive.
所罗门・诺瑟普是为数不多的
摆脱奴隶身份重获自由的绑架受害者之一
所罗门让拐卖他的人受到了审判
因为不能在国家首都对白人做出不利的证词
所罗门对奴隶主詹姆斯・伯奇的申诉失败
在纽约漫长的法律诉讼程序中
拐卖他的两人 汉密尔顿和布朗也免于起诉
1853年 所罗门出版了小说"为奴十二年"
他投身于废奴运动
在美国东北地区到处做有关奴隶制的演讲
所罗门死于何时 何处 如何而死均是未知数
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
# 去约旦河吧 #
# Went down to the River Jordan #
# 在那里 约翰曾为三个人施洗 #
# Where John baptized three #
# 当我唤醒来自地狱的恶魔时 #
# When I woke the devil in hell #
# 我告诉他是约翰为我施洗的 #
# Said Johnny baptized me #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# I said roll, Jordan, roll #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 有些人说约翰是施洗者 #
# Well, some say John was a Baptist #
# 有些人说约翰是犹太人 #
# Some say John was a Jew #
# 但我说约翰是一名牧师 #
# But I say John was a preacher #
# 因为圣经上也这么写着的 #
# 'Cause my Bible says so too #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# I said roll, Jordan, roll #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 哈利路亚 #
# Hallelujah #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 噢 流动吧 #
# Oh, roll now #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 哈利路亚 #
# Halleluiah #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 大家一起唱 #
# Everybody say #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 噢 孩子们 #
# Oh, children #
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #
# 哈利路亚 #
# Halleluiah #
你们接下来是削砍组
Y'all gonna be in a cutting gang.
小菜一碟 你们拿着刀
Very simple. I want you to take your knife.
# 流动吧 约旦河 流动吧 #
# Roll, Jordan, roll #
# 主啊 我的灵魂会升入天堂 #
# My soul will rise in heaven, Lord #
# 只要约旦河还在流动 #
# For the year when Jordan roll #